Guide to the Scott Maynes papers, 1964-2006.
Maynes, Scott papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Scott Maynes papers, 1964-2006.
23-26-3671
E. Scott(Edwin Scott), Maynes 1922-
3.4 cubic feet
Correspondence, Publications
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence,reviews, presentations, and publications, relating to Maynes' work in the Dept. of Policy Analysis and Management (formerly the Dept. of Consumer Economics and Housing) and in consumer policy making and survey research methodology.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Professor emeritus of Policy Analysis and Management, Cornell University.
Scott Maynes attended Springfield College in 1940, entered the U.S. Army Air Force in January 1943, and was discharged in December 1945. He received a B.S. in Social Sciences from Springfield College in 1947, an M.A. in Economics from Wesleyan University in 1949 and a Ph.D. in Economics from the University of Michigan in 1956. His career spanned 18 years in Economics at the University of Minnesota and 17 years in Consumer Economics at Cornell.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence,reviews, presentations, and publications, relating to Maynes' work in the Dept. of Policy Analysis and Management (formerly the Dept. of Consumer Economics and Housing) and in consumer policy making and survey research methodology.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Maynes, E. Scott1922-; Maynes, E. Scott 1922-; Cornell University--Faculty.; New York State College of Human Ecology.Dept. of Consumer Economics and Housing.
Subjects:
Economics--Methodology; Consumer behavior.; Consumers; Consumer education--study and teaching--New York (State)--Ithaca.; Consumption (Economics)
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Correspondence
Box 1
Series II. Subject Files
Boxes 2 & 3
Series III. Interviews
Box 3
Series IV. Publications
Box 3
Series V. Presentations
Box 4
Series VI. University Related Material
Box 4
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Correspondence
  - Correspondence A, 2000-2001 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence B, 1988-2005 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence B, 1988-1993 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence B, 1988-1996 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence C, 1994-2000 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence C, 1987-1993 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence D, 1986-2001 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence E, 1988-2003 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence F, 1988-2004 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence G, 1988-2000 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence H, 1994-2006 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence H, 1987-1993 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence I, 1991-1995 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence J, 1988-1997 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence K, 1992-2006 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence K, 1988-1993 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence L, 1990-2003 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence M, 1988-2005 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence M, 1990-1996 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence M, 1988-2001 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence N, 1988-2003 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence O, 1988-2005 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence P, 1988-1995 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Correspondence R, 1988-2006 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence S, 1991-2002 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence S, 1987-1990 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence T, 1987-1999 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence U and V, 1988-1995 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence W, 1989-2001 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Correspondence X-Z, 1990-2006 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - ACCI- American Council on Consumer Interests Correspondence, 1969-2001 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Advancing the Consumer Interest, 1996-2002 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Advertising, 1965-1985 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Advertising: The Economics of Illusion-notes, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Argentina- Survey of Consumer Expectations, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Series II. Subject Files
  - Barton, John Correspondence, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Book- Decision Making for Consumers- revisions/reviewers, 1991-1996 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Bristow, Barbara Correspondence, 1999-2002 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Brooks, Richard Correspondence, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Bryant, Keith Correspondence, 1971-2000 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Consumer Education- subject file, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - "Consumer Problems in Market Economies" - presentation to the Consumer Affairs Committee, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Consumer Protection- subject file, 1970-2003 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Consumer Search- subject file, 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Consumer Sovereignty- subject file, 1969-1995 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Consumerism as the 4th Force in Market Economics- U. Conn, Montana State, 1988-1993 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Consumerism as the 4th Force in Market Economics- U. Conn, Montana State, 1988-1993 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Consumers International, 1994-2003 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Consumers Union and Scott Maynes Conflict of Interest Case, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 15A)
  - Consumers Union-Annual Reports, 1974-1992 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Consumers Union Correspondence, 1991-2000 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Consumers Union Study- Questionaire, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Consumers Union- Comparative Study- Norman Leonarczyk, John Hosker, 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Consumers Union: Current Developments, 1992-1999 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Consumers Union- Visit, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Consumers Union Correspondence, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Doyle, Joe- former student, 1994-1996 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Duncan, Greg- Visit, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Financial Planning for Retirement- Cooperative Extension Talk, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Free Trade, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Grace-Martin, Karen, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Huttenrauch, Roland Article, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Information Processing: Labeling, Unit Pricing, Unfirom Product Code, 1974-1989 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Kerton, Robert Correspondence papers, 1998-2003 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Knoll, Robert Correspondence, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Kraughoff, Robert, 1996-2002 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Local Consumer Information System (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Malthusiasm- Paul Ehrlick vs. Julian Simon, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Maynes Prize Winners, 1999-2002 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Minnesota-University of- Correspondence, 1995-1999 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Mitchell, Jeremy, 1990-1997 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Morgan, James Correspondence, 1993-2002 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Nader, Ralph Correspondence articles, 1972-2003 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - National Consumer Council, 1993-2001 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Noelakanta, Bettadalli, 1997-2002 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - No-Fault Auto Insurance, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - O'Connell, Jeff, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - PAM News, 2002-2003 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Payson, Steven- Quality Measurement, 1995-1998 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Population/ Rev. Mathus (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Price-Quality Relationship- papers, 1983-1995 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Quality- lecture/articles, notes, 1964-1973 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Quality- Early papers, Correspondence notes, 1971-1987 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Quality: Uniformity of Quality- Assessments- Sharyn Adelstein, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Retirement- VP Ehrenberg, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Rhodes, Frank, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Richman, Louis, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Russe, J. Edward - Nutritional labeling, 1979, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Schultz, Robert- The Advertising Council- Sr. VP, 1990-2000 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Search for the Perfect Information Frontier, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Search/Shopping, 1991-1995 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Sibler, Norman, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Smith, Vernon, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Smoking- lawsuits concerning tobacco, 1996-1998 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Srinivasan- Maynes Project- The Efficiency of Food Consumerpiton, 1992-1993 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - State Capital Credit Union- Survey of Actual and Potential Members, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Statler Study Club Study, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Stiftung Warentest- background documents- statutes, 1981-1990 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Stiftung Warentest- Notes, 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Stiftung Warentest- Roland Huttenrauch, 1985-1989 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Stiftung Warentest, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Stiftung Warentest- Product Testing- tubler degree, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Stiftung Warentest- Biesdorf Interview, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Uniformity Data, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Wang, Chunben- Chia, 1993-1994 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Warne, Colston, 1953-2000 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Wilke, Bill- review of article "Marketing Contributions to Society", 2000 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Zick, Cathy, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Ziegler, Jerome, 1984-2000 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Series III. Interviews
  - Armand de Wasche, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Dick Westendorp, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Dr. John Beishon, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Julian Edwards, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Peter Goldman, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Daphne Gross, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Maurice Healy, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Greta Hellman, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Jennifer Jenkins, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Alastair Macgeorge, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Vivien Marles, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Nicholas Maude, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Charles Medawar, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Rosemary McRobert, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Jeremy Mitchell, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Katrina Patterson, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Derek Prentice, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - President Hunter Rawlings: First Impressions, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Joanna Reynolds, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Eirlys Roberts, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Edith Rudinger, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Peter Sand, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - John Sandringham, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Joint Staff Mgmt. Council, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - David Tench, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - John Thirlwell, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Karen Virgo, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Michael Warren, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Rachel Waterhouse, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - David Watts, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Helena Wiesner, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Anne Wrangham, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Michael Young, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Chris Zealley, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 60)
- Series IV. Publications
  - Various Publications by Scott Maynes, 1958-2003 (Box 3, Folder 61-122)
- Series V. Presentations
  - Presentations, 1994-1995 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Campus Club of Cornell, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Seminar- Market, Research for Comparative Product Testing, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Frei Universitat- Berlin, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Consumers Association, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - American Council on Consumer Interest Conference, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Johnson School of Management - Marketing Seminar, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Seoul National University, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Austrailian Consumers Association, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Far East Trip- Austrailia, Korea, Japan, New Zealand, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Korea- Samsung Corporation, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Toyko- Keidanren Kaikan Sophia University, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - China- Zhongshan University, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Austrailia- Swinburne Institute, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - China, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Consumer Affairs Committee- Bar Association of NYC, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Unitarian Church Presentation, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Universidad Torcuato DiTella, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Financial Security in Later Life In-Service, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Colston E. Warne Memorial Address- "Two Consumer Disastersa nd Their Mitigation", 2003 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Colston E. Warne Speaker- Ralph Nadar, 2004 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Series VI. University Related Material
  - TIAA-CREF initative, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - University Benefits Committee, 1998-1999 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - University Benefits Commitree, 1999-2000 (Box 4, Folder 24)